

July 1, 2015

1511 Gaspe Blvd Seneca, SC 29672 Phone: (856) 912-3510

Email: j.d.wood83@gmail.com

Citi 399 Park Avenue New York, NY 10043

Dear Recruiter,

It is with great interest that I am applying for the position of Data Scientist, Global Analytics & Insights at Citi, as posted on LinkedIn. My doctoral research on astrophysical fluid dynamics at Clemson University was almost entirely computationally based, so I have accrued an experience with multiple programming languages, including Fortran 90+, C/C++, Python, Matlab and R, in a Linux environment, as well as with profiling and debugging programs such as Intel's VTune, gdb, and Valgrind.

I have thrived at Clemson both working independently on my own project and with colleagues on course-work and their research. My coding strengths as a programming mean that I can write code correctly and document/comment appropriately for future users. At Clemson, we were required to present our research before the Astrophysics group every semester, so I also have developed strong oral and written communication skills.

I believe that I would be a terrific choice for the Data Scientist, Global Analytics & Insights position with your company. My résumé included in this application gives more details of my background, showing that I am well-qualified for this position. At the top of this document, you can find my email address and phone number which you can use to contact me for an interview; I can be reached by either method to schedule an interview.

Thank you for your time and consideration,

Joshua D Wood

# JOSHUA D WOOD

 $(856) \cdot 912 \cdot 3510 \diamond j.d.wood83@gmail.com$ 1511 Gaspe Blvd  $\diamond$  Seneca SC 29672 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jdwood983

#### **EDUCATION**

Clemson University

May 2015

Ph.D. in Physics

Dissertation: Multidimensional Simulations of Non-linear

Cosmic Ray Production in Supernova Remnant Evolution

Indiana University of Pennsylvania

August 2009

M.S. in Physics

Thesis: Optical Properties of Low-Dimensional Semiconductors

Rutgers University

May 2007

B.S. in Physics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Clemson University

Graduate Student

September 2009 - May 2015

Clemson, SC

- Solved numerical hydrodynamics and second-order differential equations using and modifying highly parallelized Fortran 90+ and C-based finite volume codes
- · Post-processing 4×61 GB datasets for synthetic emissions using Python, C++ & Fortran 90 codes
- · Instructor for multiple Laboratory classes (algebra based, calculus based)
- · Instructor on record for Introduction to Programming course (graduate only)

## University of Alabama

Research Assistant

July 2010, July 2011, May 2012

Huntsville, AL

- Research assistant to collaborator, Dr Ken-Ichi Nishikawa
- · Investigated numerical methods of hydrodynamics for dissertation
- · Investigated dynamic evolution of supernova remnants for dissertation

### Indiana University of Pennsylvania

August 2007 - August 2009

Graduate Student

Indiana, PA

- · Numerically modeling optical properties of semiconductors using Python & Fortran codes
- Operated Physics Learning Center
- · Performed outreach to local high schools

## **Rutgers University**

Sept 2006 - May 2007

Research Assistant

Camden, NJ

- · Produced thin films (micron scale) of polymers (PMMA, polystyrene) using laser ablation
- Studied surface morphology of thin films via AFM and electron microscope

### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Fortran 90+, C/C++, Latex, Lua, Python, Bash, Matlab/Octave

Excel & Powerpoint (and equivalent), some SQL, R & Hadoop

Numerical Methods Numerical integration/differentiation, finite difference/volume methods,

Monte Carlo, regular expressions, linear algebra, discretization

imputation, MPI, OpenMP

Operating Systems Linux (primary OS), Unix, Windows

### DEPARTMENTAL SERVICES

## Clemson University

September 2010 - May 2015

- $\cdot$  Organized weekly intra-departmental seminar
- · Moderator for graduate student listserv
- · Graduate student liaison for faculty hiring committee (Spring 2012)